Guide to the Colt Press Records, 1920-1973
Department of Special Collections
- FINANCIAL PAPERS
  - INVOICES - A: Elizabeth Agee Bookshelf; Alameda City Library; American News Co.; Ames Bookshop; Amherst College Library; Argonaut Bookshop; Argus; Bookshop; L.S. Ayres and Co. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - INVOICES - B: Mr. P.A. Bailey; William M. Bains; Baker and Taylor Co.; Ball State Book Store; Bennett and Marshall; Bern Porter Books; Albert Bonnier Pulbishing House; The Book Cache; Book Clearing House; Book and Magazine Shop; Book of the Month Club Inc.; Bookhunters; Bookmark; Books Inc.; Book Shelf; Bookshop of Lucy Wilder; James R. Brehm; Brentano's Inc.; Albert Britnell Book Shop; Herbert F. Brown; J.E. & K.F. Brown; Brown Univ. Library; Bryant Bookshop; Mrs. Neil Buckley; Buffalo Public Library; Univ. of Buffalo - Locwood Memorial Library. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - INVOICES - C: Univ. of Calif., Berkeley; Univ. of Calif., Los Angeles; Univ. of Calif., Medical Libran Calif. School Book Dep'y; Campbell's Book Store; Campus Bookstore - Univ. of Kentucky; Campus Textbook Exchange; Stephen Capernaros; H.C. Capwell Co.; Carnegie Library of Atlanta Beatrice Carpenter; Philip Case; Dan Castro; Nicholas Cataldo; Centaur Bookshop; Mrs. Joseph Chamberlain; Chaucer Head Bookshop; Stuart Chevalier; Univ. of Chicago Bookstore; Chiswick Bookshop; Claitor's Bookshop; College Book Exchange; College Shop - Mills College; Columbia University Bookstore; Library of Congress; State of Conn.; Constantia Booksellers; Consumers' Book Cooperative, Inc.; Cooperative Bookstore, Univ. of Tenn; Cornell Univ. Library; Edith M. Coulter; J.C. Crews; J.V. Cunningham; Mrs. Arthur C. Curtner. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - INVOICES - D-G: Daliel's; Harmer E. Davis; Dawson's Bookshop; James Ladd Delkia; Denver Art Museum; May Dormin, Doubleday Doran Bookshop; Chaplain E.T. DuBrau; Duke Univ.; Philip D. Duschnes; Dutton's Inc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Eastern Book Co.; Harvey Eastling; Edward Eberstadt and Son; Paul Elder & Son; Prof. Albert Elkus; Charles Elkus; Elsa Gift Shop; The Emporium; Mrs. Edmund Engel; Euclid Book Co.
  - The Fair; Edith Farnsworth Bookshop; Mr. Francis Farquhar; Field's Bookstore; Fowler Brothers; Fresno Bookshop; Gardner's Bookshop.
  - Gelber Lileinthal Inc.; Gellert's Bookstore; Georgia State Women's College; J.K. Gill Co.; Glen Bros. Music Co.; Gotham Book Mart; Gould, Mrs. Lilly B; Gramercy Bookshop; Gran, Anthony; Grauer, Ben; Grolier Bookshop.
  - INVOICES - H-L: Hagedorn Bookshop; Hartman, Harry; Harvard College Library; Harvard Bookstore; Harvard Cooperative; Haunted Bookshop; A. & W. Head Inc; Hersholt, Mr. Jean; Hill's Stationery Store; Hirshberg, Harry H; Holliday, J.J.; Holliday Bookshop; Hollywood Bookstore; Holman's, Holmes Book Col.; Houston Bookstore; John Howell Bookstore; J.L. Hudson Co.; Marian Hunter Bookshop; Hunter College; Huntington Bookstore; Huntington Library. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Innon, Mr. M.G.; Illinois Institute of Technology; Immaculate Heart College; Indiana University.
  - Jeffreys, Louis [Lewis]; John Hopkins Univ.; Johnson's Bookstore.
  - Kees, Mrs. John; John G. Kidd and Son; Alfred A. Knopf; Kroch's Bookstore, Inc.
  - Lambert Grant Inc.; T.&J. Lawrence Bookstore Dr. Milton Levine; Curtis Lindsay; Laurence Livingston; Leon Livingston Ad Agency; B.W. Lucas College Book Co.; Dr. Henry Lund; Dr. George D. Lyman.
  - INVOICES - M-N: Malcolm MacNeil & Co.; David Magee; Main Street Bookstore; Marshall Field & Co.; Laurence R. Maxwell; J.A. McCleary; A.C. McClurg & Co.; Cpl. Robert J. McLaughlin; McMurray's; Paul McPharlin; Miami Univ.; Thomas More Books, Jules Megeff; Methodist Publishing House, Univ. of Michigan Miller's; Henry Morgan & Co. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - The Nation; National Bibliophile Service; New Mexico Bookstore; New York Public Library; John L. Newbegin; Newman Bookshop; Nichols School.
  - INVOICES - O-S: Oakland Public Library; Oakland Public Schools; Occidental College Bookstore; DeWitt O'Kieffe; Duncan H. Olmstead; Ormsby Book Service (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Peninsula Bookshop; Perine Book Co.; Personal Bookshop; Post Purchasing and Contracting Office; Price's Order Service; Princeton Univ. Store; Progressive Bookshop
  - Queens Borough Public Library
  - Graham Ray Bookshop; Reserve Bookstore; Richmond Memorial Library; J.W. Robinson, Co.; Paul Romaine; Rosenbach Co.
  - St. Mary of the Springs College; St. Paul Book Co.; William Salloch; San Francisco News Co.; Sather Gate Bookshop; Satyr Bookshop; Schill's Bookshop; Scribner Bookshop; Sherman Clay Co.; Sherwood's Inc.; Skidmore College Library; Southwest Museum; Mrs. Jessie Spear; Don Stanford; Stanford Bookstore; Stanford Univ. Bookstore; G.E. Stecher and Co.; Stechert-Hofner Co.; Stewart's Inc; Walter Stoddard; Stokes and Stockell Bookshop; Lee Stopple; A.D. Storrs; Cpl. Dave L. Swank Jr.
  - INVOICES - T-Z: Andrew A. Tagaris; Tecolote Bookshop; James L. Thielman; G. Harrison Thomson; Tulsa Bookshop; Otto Ulbrich; United States International Book Assc. Inc.; University Bookstore - Columbia, Missouri; University Book Store; Vanguard Booksellers' Vassar Cooperative Bookshop; University of Virginia; Vincent Vodrazka; A.C. Vroman Inc; S/Sgt. Eugene Walter; Mrs. John I. Walter; John Wanamaker; Central Washington College of Education; Wayne University; Wellesley College Library; James M. Wells; Westwood Bookstore; Emil White; The White House; Mrs. William Whitlock; Whyte Bookshop; Vern Cleghorn Wilkins; Dr. Ernest H. Willers; Dr. George A. Williamson; Carl K. Wilson; Wold Bookshop; College of Wooster; William Wreden (Wreden's Bookshop); Charles Yate Bookstore. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - INVOICES: REVERSE CHRONOLOGICAL - 1946 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - INVOICES: # 735 - 1053 11/40-12/40. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - INVOICES: # 5670 - 8867 12/46-7/47 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - INVOICES: # 8868 - 8954 7/47 - 10/47 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - INVOICES: # 8955 - 9098 10/47- 3/49 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - RECEIPTS: A.C. Gollan & Son; Korsmeier & Swanson; Matson Securities; Wm. S. Millerick Co., Inc.; William T. Wheeler. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - CANCELLED CHECKS: 9/41 - 4/42 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - CANCELLED CHECKS: 5/42 - 12/43 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - CANCELLED CHECKS: 1/44 - 6/45 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - CANCELLED CHECKS: 7/45 - 2/47 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - DEBIT SLIPS: 10/41 - 9/42, 3/44 - 12/47 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - BANK STATEMENTS: 1941, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - BANK STATEMENTS: 1948, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - BANK STATEMENTS: 1949 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Stationery and envelopes (blank) (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - ACCOUNT BOOK: 1938 - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - ACCOUNT BOOK: 1939 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - ACCOUNT BOOK: 1943 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Account reports & inventories (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Income tax returns (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Financial matters misc. (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Contracts (Box 6, Folder 58)
- MISCELLANEOUS: (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - 1. Death and Inebriation, poem by Rachel Whimsey -, typescript
  - 2. For the Christening of Boofy's Litter of Puppies, typescript of a poem., 1p.
  - 3. Saroyan - He's Wonderful - by Jane Grabhorn, typescript 9pp. (2 copies)
  - 4. A Rondeau for Jane Bissell Grabhorn on Her Birthday, typescript poem.
  - 5. Typescript - translation of a Review (on The Colussus of Maroussi) by M.J. Politis published in in the National Herald, Greek Daily of New York, issue November 27th, 1941., 5pp.
  - 6. Wedding invitation, 1946
  - 7. Lease between Gordon F. Hurst and Mrs. Robert Grabhorn. July 17, 1939.
  - 8. Invitation to a previewing of typographical work of Jane Grabhorn, 1956(two).
  - 9. Seller's Permit - Jane Grabhorn (two)
  - 10. Christmas greeting card
  - 11. Stationery & envelopes - Jumbo Press, Colt Press, Grabhorn Press, (10 pieces)
  - 12. Typescript of a poem by George Montague, Earl of Sandwich. A Reminder. Originally inserted in the copy of In a Green Shade.
  - 13. Typescripts of a poem by George Montague - A Woodland Garden
  - 14. A handwritten note inserted in In a Green Shade - description and explanation of numbers 12 & 13
  - 15. Miscellaneous notes and scraps of papers, (5 pieces)
  - 16. Two xerox copies
  - 17. Original linoleum block by Mallette Dean
  - 18. 2 unpublished manuscripts (fragment - typed).
- NEWSCLIPPINGS RE: Jane Grabhorn, her work, books printed by Colt Press, Colt Press (Box 7, Folder 60)
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Ink drawings by various artists for vignettes (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Manuscript of The Better Mouse Trap by Jane Grabhorn (Box 7, Folder 63)
- Awards of Merit - Rounce & Coffin, Western Books, American Institute of Graphic Arts (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Jumbo Press -, 10 designs for book plates (Box 7, Folder 65)
- 1. Jane Grabhorn's (?) typescript notes: a. Author's Note, b. Cherchez La Femme (Box 7, Folder 66)
- 2. Typescript - The Union Street Car, 2pp.
- 3. Typescript - The Jumbo Press - Before and After, 2pp.
- 4. Typescript - no - title -, 12pp.
- INK DRAWINGS:
  - 1. Eleven drawings by Otis Oldfield (those drawings which are signed were used in the book McTeague)
  - 2. Two drawings by Sotomayor(?)
MATERIAL TRANSFERRED TO SPECIAL COLLECTIONS
Group One: PRINTED EPHEMERA
1. Booklet: From Mumbo Jumbo and her Nephew to Paul Maul - Dools from the Barstools. Jumbo Press.
2. Advertisement for A Guide and Handbook for Amateurs of Printing. Jumbo Press (two).
3. Booklet: Frederic W. Goudy - a Confidential Interview. Jumbo Press.
4. Booklet: Reverting to Type by Jane Grabhorn. Red Tower Press.
5. Five loose pages - Reverting to Type.
6. A Typographic Discourse for the Distaff Side of Printing, a Book by Ladies. Jumbo Press, 1937. 12 loose pages
7. Advertisement - Jumbo Press
8. Birth Announcement - 1957
9. Proof with draft of illumination
10. 2×3 printed note re: recital given at Miss Leila's
11. A Typographic Solecism
12. Printed invitation to Harold Seeger's birthday - May 9, 1939
13. Acrolades From the Press
14. An Evening with Fred Goudy. Invitation to a dinner honoring Goudy - June 10, 1940
GROUP TWO
1. Printed birthday greetings printed by Jumbo Press to Frederic Goudy
2. Fragment of a printed story about Goudy
3. A Guide & Handbook for Amateurs of Printing. Jumbo Press - 1937
4. Printed poem with illustration of a cat
5. Coverslip- Keepsake 1938 - Pilgrimage to Deepdene
6. Guest Book - cover - for the marriage of Marie Louise & Jackson Burke - 1937,illuminated.
GROUP THREE
1. Fragment by William Saroyan - printed by Jumbo Press for Albert M. Bender
2. An Fragment Unpublished by the Jumbo Press - manuscript of printed material inserted.
3. Individuality by M. Landi. Printed by Jane & Robert Grabhorn, 1971
4. Show bill - 1937,Diana Dane, performing - announcement of date and location of performance
5. Swing Low Sweet Sherwood (two)
6. Block print - series of elephant figures - symbol of Jumbo Press
7. Melissa Wilson's a wearin' the Green Sleeves, March 17, 1945
8. Block print - Jumbo Press 1937(two)
9. Printed letter - Martha Jane to Mother
10. Printed broadside entitled Oh Dearly Beloved
11. Printed Broadside - And So...
12. Uncut pages of A Typographic Discourse (6 pages)
GROUP FOUR
1. Specimen Pages - The Colussus of Maroussi, H. Wolff Book Manufacturing Co., New York, 1941(three)
2. Specimen Page - The Pragmatic Test, H. Wolff Book Manufacturing Co., New York, 1941
3. Specimen Page - Yvor Winters, H. Wolff Book Manufacturing Co. New York, 1942
4. Publication announcement - The Letters of Frank Norris, 1956
5. Advertisement - Announcement of new books from Colt Press
6. Booklet - Life & Hard Times or Sherwood Grover's 25 Years with the Grabhorn Press, 1968
7. Chapter fragment - Chapter 1 - Conversation between Nynheer and Horatio (2 pages)
8. Colt Forty-Five, 1956
9. Birthday greetings to Robert Grabhorn, May 7, 1970
10. Invitation to a dinner honoring Albert Sperisen, 1942
11. Announcement of birthday celebration for Robert Grabhorn's 36th birthday - in French
12. Five proofs - with illuminations
13. Printed invitation from Dr. & Mrs. A.W. Ward
14. Invitation to a Christmas Gathering
15. Printed Poem - Lullabye, signed Marie Louise Burke, Sept. 15, 1939
16. Poem - With no Raison d'Etre but Instead of a Lettre March 4, 1952
17. Broadside of a poem - no title - 1st line - Who's that lying in the middle of the floor...
18. Jan the Dutch Barge Dog by Victoria Bissell, 1960
19. Happy New Year Greetings - 1953
20. Printed poem by Johathan Swift - greeting card from Jane & Robert Grabhorn
21. Easter greeting card
22. Negroes of America by Tommy Bransten
GROUP FIVE
1. Revolt of a Tired Typesetter, Grabhorn Press, 1958
2. The Brothers the Mothers by Jane Grabhorn, Grace Hoper Press, 1966
3. Booklet: description of books printed in 1940and the possibilities for 1941
4. The Colt Springs High for 1940,description of books in print and for sale.
5. A Checklist of Colt Press Books, list of books printed during 1938-1942
6. Colt Press First Anniversary 1939,description of books in print and out of print
7. Printed note to customers re: progress of the Press
8. Book Order Forms - Colt Press (6)
9. Address mailing slips (4)
10. List of Colt Press books for sale
11. The Terry-Broderick Duel by Carroll Douglas Hall Advertisement introducing the above book to Colt Press patrons
12. Announcement of publication of California- Spanish Proverbs collected and translated by Mildred Yorba Macarthur.
13. Proofs for the Colt Press Epicure Series
14. Announcement of an exhibition of typographical work of Jane Grabhorn
15. Announcement of exhibition of Colt Press Books
16. Advertisement for Maurizius Forever by Henry Miller
17. Colt Press newsletter - August 1941, two inserts - loose
18. Advertisements for The Colussus of Maroussi by Henry Miller (two)
19. Colt Press Newsletter Dec. 1941
20. Advertisement for Lala Montez by Oscar Lewis
21. Invitation to an exhibit re: Jane Grabhorn & the Colt Press presented by American Institute of Graphic Arts
GROUP SIX
1. Broadside: announcement of exhibit of Jumbo & Colt Press books - April 7, 1956
2. Broadside: Christmas Gifts for Lovers - list of various Colt Press books for sale - 1943
3. Book covers: 1. The Colussus of Maroussi, 2. Omai, 3. The Wife of Martin Guerre, 4. The Boys in the Back Room, 5. Note Books of Night
4. Legal agreement between Colt Press and George Ezra Dave re: subscription to all books issued by the Press
5. Announcement of an exhibit & sale of drawings by Otis Oldfield for Colt Press publication of McTeague
6. Title page for the book McTeague by Frank Norris
7. List of books in print and to be printed by the Colt Press
8. Books for Spring from the Colt Press (two)
9. Proof for the pamphlet entitled Colt Press First Anniversary 1939
10. Broadside: Agreement between Colt Press and George Eckhardt entitling Eckhardt to one volume of every book printed by Colt Press, signed Jane Grabhorn, Sept. 22, 1967
GROUP SEVEN
1. Proof for cover of The Gold Rush Song Book
2. Concerning a Cat - Letters from my Nephew 1961
3. Broadside: Songs of the Grabhorn Press - The Ballad of Robert O'Grabhorn
4. Broadside: Travel Tips: from Highly - Seasoned Old Traveler Jane Grabhorn to Ruth Woods, June 20, 1955
5. Broadside: Go Go Go!
6. Broadside: story about Harold Seeger in celebration of his 43rd birthday, 1942
7. Birthday greeting to Robert Grabhorn from Jane Grabhorn for his 68th birthday entitled Once Again into the Breeches
8. Broadside: printed by Jane Grabhorn for Albert M. Bender, 1939,poetry re: St. Patrick
9. Proof sheet for the title page of Wedding Book, 1938
10. Broadside: Individuality by M. Landi printed by Jane & Robert Grabhorn, 1971
11. Broadside: invitation to a party at the Grabhorn Press
12. Broadside: invitation to celebration of R. Grabhorn's 46th birthday, 1946
13. Broadside: A Valentine for Jane
14. Broadside: Ode to a Returning Voyager, Florence Walter, Nov. 2, 1957
15. Broadside: 1st line - Paul, oh Paul, why do you sell hides?
16. Broadside: birthday greeting to Bill on his 56th birthday
17. Broadside: The Whorscope of Sherwood Bissell Grover
18. Broadside: Mama to Papa
19. Broadside: Superwoman Lil
20. Broadside: O Bill dear Bill
21. Broadside: Printed for Margie Pratt by Jane Grabhorn
22. Broadside: birthday greeting to Bill for his 60th birthday, Jan. 7, 1970
23. Broadside: birthday greeting to Robert Grabhorn for his 50th birthday, May 17, 1950
24. Broadside: The City
25. Broadside: get well card addressed to David from [Jane & Robert] Grabhorn
26. Broadside: A tooth for a tooth
27. Broadside: Friday 13
28. Broadside: Thanksgiving message for Nov. 27, 1970
29. Broadside: To My Friends
GROUP EIGHT
1. Poster re: the book Omai, First Polynesian Ambassador to England
2. Poster re: the book Garden Date
3. Poster re: the book The Epicure in Hawaii
4. Photostat of reviews
5. Broadside re: the book The Colussus of Maroussi
6. Broadside: Pilgrimage to Rampart
7. Broadsides: Wedding Book - Carol Walter, Henry Sinton - 1938,(four)
8. Broadside: Birthday Boy Breaks Bookies - Grabhorn Scores Fifty-Five
9. Broadside: La Tosca bar sinister
10. Broadside: Fellow Hamburghers
11. Broadside: birthday greeting for Robert Grabhorn, 1969
12. Broadside: Who was that lady I seen you with?
13. Go Grover Go!, salute to Sherwood P. Grover, 1954
14. Pencil sketches of Robert Grabhorn (2)
BOOKS
1. Grabhorn, Jane. Robert Arlie Grabhorn, a Portrait, Jumbo Press, May 17, 1938
2. Montagu, George - Earl of Sandwich. The Bridle-Way Elkin Mathews Limited, London, 1925,autographed
3. Montague, George - Earl of Sandwich. In a Green Shade, Elkin Mathews & Marrot, Ltd., London, 1928autographed
4. Montague, George - Earl of Sandwich. Windows, same as above, 1924,autographed
5. The Epicure in Hawaii, Honolulu Star - Bulletin, Hawaii, Colt Press, 1938